<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/DTDs/Podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0">
<channel>
<title>NotebookLM Reviews of Economics</title>
<link></link>
<language>en-us</language>
<itunes:author>Sebastian Kranz</itunes:author>
<description><![CDATA[NotebookLM audio deep dives into selected open access articles from the <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/economics">Annual Review of Economics</a>. Generated using Google's <a href="https://notebooklm.google/NotebookLM">NotebookLM</a>.

This podcast is a private project from <a href="https://www.uni-ulm.de/mawi/mawi-wiwi/institut/mitarbeiter/skranz/">Sebastian Kranz (Ulm University)</a> and not endorsed in any way by the journal or the authors of the underlying articles.

Personally, I really like these audio deep dives. But don't forget that AI can still hallucinate and make other mistakes.

To the best of my knowledge, all underlying articles have been published under a <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International</a> license.

]]></description>
<itunes:owner>
  <itunes:name>Sebastian Kranz</itunes:name>
  <itunes:email>sebastian.kranz@uni-ulm.de</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<image>
  <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/skranz/are_podcast/main/cover_review_economics.png</url>
  <title>NotebookLM Reviews of Economics</title>
</image>
<itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/skranz/are_podcast/main/cover_review_economics.png"/>
<itunes:category text="Science">
  <itunes:category text="Social Sciences"/>
</itunes:category>

<itunes:category text="Government">
  <itunes:category text="Politics"/>
</itunes:category>

<itunes:category text="Education">
  <itunes:category text="Higher Education"/>
</itunes:category>    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
<itunes:keywords>economics, research, annual review of economics, AI narration, deep dive, notebooklm</itunes:keywords>



<item>
  <title>Automation: Theory, Evidence, and Outlook (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-090523-113355">"Automation: Theory, Evidence, and Outlook"</a> (2024) by Pascual Restrepo (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article reviews the literature on automation and its impact on labor markets, wages, factor shares, and productivity. I first introduce the task model and explain why this framework offers a compelling way to think about recent labor market trends and the effects of automation technologies. The task model clarifies that automation technologies operate by substituting capital for labor in a widening range of tasks. This substitution reduces costs, creating a positive productivity effect, but it also reduces employment opportunities for workers displaced from automated tasks, creating a negative displacement effect. I survey the empirical literature and conclude that there is wide qualitative support for the implications of task models and the displacement effects of automation. I conclude by discussing shortcomings of the existing literature and avenues for future research.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-090523-113355/Automation_and_Its_Impact_on_Labor_Markets.mp3" length="12327276" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-090523-113355</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Industrial Policy and the Great Divergence (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091523-044259">"Industrial Policy and the Great Divergence"</a> (2024) by Réka Juhász; Claudia Steinwender (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We discuss recent work evaluating the role of the government in shaping the economy during the long nineteenth century, a practice we refer to as industrial policy. States deployed a vast variety of different policies aimed primarily, but not exclusively, at fostering industrialization. A thin but growing literature has started to evaluate the economic effects of these policies, but many questions remain open for study.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091523-044259/Nineteenth_Century_Industrial_Policy_A_Review.mp3" length="47685958" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091523-044259</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 08:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Understanding Spatial Agglomeration: Increasing Returns, Land, and Transportation Costs (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-020723-041113">"Understanding Spatial Agglomeration: Increasing Returns, Land, and Transportation Costs"</a> (2024) by Hans R.A. Koster; Jacques-François Thisse (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Economic activities are concentrated on a small share of inhabitable land. In our view, this agglomeration is the outcome of a trade-off between increasing returns and transportation costs, which capitalizes into land rents. Our second baseline idea is that Tiebout-like sorting provides a general framework to handle a large array of problems in spatial economics. Cities have high housing prices because they are productive and offer high levels of amenities and public goods. Both production and amenity effects capitalize in the land rent at a particular location. Through the process of bidding for land, spatial sorting is the involuntary consequence of a myriad of individual decisions made by agents who pursue their own interests.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-020723-041113/Spatial_Economics_Agglomeration_Land_and_Sorting.mp3" length="20747333" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-020723-041113</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 05:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Experiments About Institutions (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091823-031317">"Experiments About Institutions"</a> (2024) by Michael Callen; Jonathan L. Weigel; Noam Yuchtman (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Institutions are a key determinant of economic growth, but the critical junctures in which institutions can change are not precisely defined. For example, such junctures are often identified ex post, raising several methodological problems: a selection on the outcome of institutional change; an inability to study beliefs, which are central to coordination and thus the process of institutional change; and an inability to conduct experiments to identify causal effects. We argue that critical junctures are identifiable in real time as moments of deep uncertainty about future institutions. Consistent with this conception, the papers reviewed (a) examine changes to institutions, i.e., the fundamental rules of the game; (b) are real-time studies of plausible critical junctures; and (c) use field experiments to achieve causal identification. We also advocate for more systematic measurement of beliefs about future institutions to identify critical junctures as they happen and provide an empirical proof of concept. Such work is urgent given contemporary critical junctures arising from democratic backsliding, state fragility, climate change, and conflicts over the rights of the marginalized.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091823-031317/Experiments_About_Institutions.mp3" length="14371764" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091823-031317</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 05:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Moral Boundaries (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091223-093730">"Moral Boundaries"</a> (2024) by Benjamin Enke (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article reviews the growing economics literature that studies the politico-economic impacts of heterogeneity in moral boundaries across individuals and cultures. The so-called universalism-versus-particularism cleavage has emerged as a main organizing principle behind various salient features of contemporary political competition, including individual-level and spatial variation in voting, the realignment of rich liberals and poor conservatives, the internal structure of ideology, and the moral content of political messaging. A recurring theme is that the explanatory power of universalism for left-wing policy views and voting is considerably larger than that of traditional economic variables. Looking at the origins of heterogeneity in universalism, an emerging consensus is that cross-group variation is partly economically functional and reflects that morality evolved to support cooperation in economic production. This insight organizes much work on how kinship systems, market exposure, political institutions, and ecology have shaped universalism through their impacts on the relative benefits of localized and impersonal interactions.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091223-093730/Moral_Boundaries_in_Political_Economy.mp3" length="27460285" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091223-093730</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 05:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Technology and the Global Economy (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-080218-025541">"Technology and the Global Economy"</a> (2024) by Jonathan Eaton; Samuel Kortum (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Interpreting individual heterogeneity in terms of probability theory has proved powerful in connecting behavior at the individual and aggregate levels. Returning to Ricardo's focus on comparative efficiency as a basis for international trade, much recent quantitative equilibrium modeling of the global economy builds on particular probabilistic assumptions about technology. We review these assumptions and discuss how they deliver a unified framework underlying a wide range of static and dynamic equilibrium models.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-080218-025541/Technology_and_the_Global_Economy.mp3" length="26720078" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-080218-025541</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 06:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>A Practical Guide to Weak Instruments (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-092123-111021">"A Practical Guide to Weak Instruments"</a> (2024) by Michael P. Keane; Timothy Neal (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We survey the weak instrumental variables (IV) literature with the aim of giving simple advice to applied researchers. This literature focuses heavily on the problem of size inflation in two-stage least squares (2SLS) two-tailed t-tests that arises if instruments are weak. A common standard for acceptable instrument strength is a first-stage F of 10, which renders this size inflation modest. However, 2SLS suffers from other important problems that exist at much higher levels of instrument strength. In particular, 2SLS standard errors tend to be artificially small in samples where the 2SLS estimate is close to ordinary least squares (OLS). This power asymmetry means the t-test has inflated power to detect false positive effects when the OLS bias is positive. The Anderson-Rubin (AR) test avoids this problem and should be used in lieu of the t-test even with strong instruments. We illustrate the practical importance of this issue in IV papers published in the American Economic Review from 2011 to 2023. Use of the AR test often reverses t-test results. In particular, IV estimates that are close to OLS and significant according to the t-test are often insignificant according to AR. We also show that for first-stage F in the 10–20 range there is a high probability that OLS estimates will be closer to the truth than 2SLS. Hence we advocate a higher standard of instrument strength in applied work.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-092123-111021/Better_Practices_for_Instrumental_Variables_Estimation.mp3" length="15010374" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-092123-111021</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Fertility in High-Income Countries: Trends, Patterns, Determinants, and Consequences (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-081523-013750">"Fertility in High-Income Countries: Trends, Patterns, Determinants, and Consequences"</a> (2024) by David E. Bloom; Michael Kuhn; Klaus Prettner (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  High-income countries have generally experienced falling fertility in recent decades. In most of these countries, the total fertility rate is now below the level that implies a stable population in the long run. This has led to concerns among economists, policymakers, and the wider public about the economic consequences of low fertility and population decline. In this contribution, we aim to (a) describe the main determinants of low fertility in high-income countries, (b) assess its potential economic consequences, (c) discuss adjustment mechanisms for individuals and economies, (d) propose a simple economic framework to analyze the long-run economic impacts of low fertility, and (e) draw lessons for economic policymakers to react appropriately. While the economic challenges of low fertility are substantial, a thoughtful and consistent policy response can mitigate most of the adverse consequences.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-081523-013750/Economics_of_Fertility_and_Population_Decline.mp3" length="17453747" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-081523-013750</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Modern Industrial Policy and the World Trade Organization (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-100223-041958">"Modern Industrial Policy and the World Trade Organization"</a> (2024) by Chad P. Bown (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article surveys the economics of industrial policy as it relates to the World Trade Organization (WTO). Motivated by concern that the modern use of industrial policy is emerging in ways that threaten cooperation in the international trading system, the article begins with the basic historical economic framework for tying industrial policy to underlying market failures. It then introduces the dominant economic understanding of the role played by the WTO, examining the WTO's rules on subsidies (and thus industrial policy), the unease with the evolution of the trading system's subsidy rules, gaps in knowledge, and important data and measurement shortcomings. The main part of the article examines four areas in which modern industrial policy operates differently and has become especially important for the trading system: China, supply chain resilience, supply chain responsiveness, and climate change. The article identifies the evidence to date, open questions, and potential paths forward for economic research to help inform policymakers’ efforts to restore international economic cooperation in trade and industrial policy.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-100223-041958/Industrial_Policy_Subsidies_and_the_WTO.mp3" length="20903191" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-100223-041958</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>The New Economics of Industrial Policy (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-081023-024638">"The New Economics of Industrial Policy"</a> (2024) by Réka Juhász; Nathan Lane; Dani Rodrik (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We discuss the considerable literature that has developed in recent years providing rigorous evidence on how industrial policies work. This literature is a significant improvement over the earlier generation of empirical work, which was largely correlational and marred by interpretational problems. On the whole, the recent crop of papers offers a more positive take on industrial policy. We review the standard rationales and critiques of industrial policy and provide a broad overview of new empirical approaches to measurement. We discuss how the recent literature, paying close attention to measurement, causal inference, and economic structure, is offering a nuanced and contextual understanding of the effects of industrial policy. We re-evaluate the East Asian experience with industrial policy in light of recent results. Finally, we conclude by reviewing how industrial policy is being reshaped by a new understanding of governance, a richer set of policy instruments beyond subsidies, and the reality of deindustrialization.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-081023-024638/The_New_Economics_of_Industrial_Policy.mp3" length="18116291" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-081023-024638</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>



</channel>
</rss>
