<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/DTDs/Podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0">
<channel>
<title>NotebookLM Reviews of Economics</title>
<link></link>
<language>en-us</language>
<itunes:author>Sebastian Kranz</itunes:author>
<description><![CDATA[NotebookLM audio deep dives into selected open access articles from the <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/economics">Annual Reviews of Economics</a>. Generated using Google's <a href="https://notebooklm.google/NotebookLM">NotebookLM</a>.

This podcast is a private project from <a href="https://www.uni-ulm.de/mawi/mawi-wiwi/institut/mitarbeiter/skranz/">Sebastian Kranz (Ulm University)</a> and not endorsed in any way by the journal or the authors of the underlying articles.

Personally, I really like these audio deep dives. But don't forget that AI can still hallucinate and make other mistakes.

To the best of my knowledge, all underlying articles have been published under a <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International</a>license.

]]></description>
<itunes:owner>
  <itunes:name>Sebastian Kranz</itunes:name>
  <itunes:email>sebastian.kranz@uni-ulm.de</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<image>
  <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/skranz/are_podcast/main/cover_review_economics.png</url>
  <title>NotebookLM Reviews of Economics</title>
</image>
<itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/skranz/are_podcast/main/logo_podcast_square.png"/>
<itunes:category text="Science">
  <itunes:category text="Social Sciences"/>
</itunes:category>

<itunes:category text="Government">
  <itunes:category text="Politics"/>
</itunes:category>

<itunes:category text="Education">
  <itunes:category text="Higher Education"/>
</itunes:category>    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
<itunes:keywords>economics, research, annual review of economics, AI narration, deep dive, notebooklm</itunes:keywords>



<item>
  <title>Automation: Theory, Evidence, and Outlook (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-090523-113355">"Automation: Theory, Evidence, and Outlook"</a> (2024) by Pascual Restrepo (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article reviews the literature on automation and its impact on labor markets, wages, factor shares, and productivity. I first introduce the task model and explain why this framework offers a compelling way to think about recent labor market trends and the effects of automation technologies. The task model clarifies that automation technologies operate by substituting capital for labor in a widening range of tasks. This substitution reduces costs, creating a positive productivity effect, but it also reduces employment opportunities for workers displaced from automated tasks, creating a negative displacement effect. I survey the empirical literature and conclude that there is wide qualitative support for the implications of task models and the displacement effects of automation. I conclude by discussing shortcomings of the existing literature and avenues for future research.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-090523-113355/Automation_and_Its_Impact_on_Labor_Markets.mp3" length="12327276" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-090523-113355</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Industrial Policy and the Great Divergence (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091523-044259">"Industrial Policy and the Great Divergence"</a> (2024) by Réka Juhász; Claudia Steinwender (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We discuss recent work evaluating the role of the government in shaping the economy during the long nineteenth century, a practice we refer to as industrial policy. States deployed a vast variety of different policies aimed primarily, but not exclusively, at fostering industrialization. A thin but growing literature has started to evaluate the economic effects of these policies, but many questions remain open for study.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091523-044259/Nineteenth_Century_Industrial_Policy_A_Review.mp3" length="47685958" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091523-044259</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 08:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>



</channel>
</rss>
