<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/DTDs/Podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0">
<channel>
<title>NotebookLM Reviews of Economics</title>
<link></link>
<language>en-us</language>
<itunes:author>Sebastian Kranz</itunes:author>
<description><![CDATA[NotebookLM audio deep dives into selected open access articles from the <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/economics">Annual Review of Economics</a>. Generated using Google's <a href="https://notebooklm.google/NotebookLM">NotebookLM</a>.

This podcast is a private project from <a href="https://www.uni-ulm.de/mawi/mawi-wiwi/institut/mitarbeiter/skranz/">Sebastian Kranz (Ulm University)</a> and not endorsed in any way by the journal or the authors of the underlying articles.

Personally, I really like these audio deep dives. But don't forget that AI can still hallucinate and make other mistakes.

To the best of my knowledge, all underlying articles have been published under a <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International</a> license.

]]></description>
<itunes:owner>
  <itunes:name>Sebastian Kranz</itunes:name>
  <itunes:email>sebastian.kranz@uni-ulm.de</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<image>
  <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/skranz/are_podcast/main/cover_review_economics.png</url>
  <title>NotebookLM Reviews of Economics</title>
</image>
<itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/skranz/are_podcast/main/cover_review_economics.png"/>
<itunes:category text="Science">
  <itunes:category text="Social Sciences"/>
</itunes:category>

<itunes:category text="Government">
  <itunes:category text="Politics"/>
</itunes:category>

<itunes:category text="Education">
  <itunes:category text="Higher Education"/>
</itunes:category>    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
<itunes:keywords>economics, research, annual review of economics, AI narration, deep dive, notebooklm</itunes:keywords>



<item>
  <title>Automation: Theory, Evidence, and Outlook (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-090523-113355">"Automation: Theory, Evidence, and Outlook"</a> (2024) by Pascual Restrepo (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article reviews the literature on automation and its impact on labor markets, wages, factor shares, and productivity. I first introduce the task model and explain why this framework offers a compelling way to think about recent labor market trends and the effects of automation technologies. The task model clarifies that automation technologies operate by substituting capital for labor in a widening range of tasks. This substitution reduces costs, creating a positive productivity effect, but it also reduces employment opportunities for workers displaced from automated tasks, creating a negative displacement effect. I survey the empirical literature and conclude that there is wide qualitative support for the implications of task models and the displacement effects of automation. I conclude by discussing shortcomings of the existing literature and avenues for future research.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-090523-113355/Automation_and_Its_Impact_on_Labor_Markets.mp3" length="12327276" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-090523-113355</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Industrial Policy and the Great Divergence (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091523-044259">"Industrial Policy and the Great Divergence"</a> (2024) by Réka Juhász; Claudia Steinwender (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We discuss recent work evaluating the role of the government in shaping the economy during the long nineteenth century, a practice we refer to as industrial policy. States deployed a vast variety of different policies aimed primarily, but not exclusively, at fostering industrialization. A thin but growing literature has started to evaluate the economic effects of these policies, but many questions remain open for study.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091523-044259/Nineteenth_Century_Industrial_Policy_A_Review.mp3" length="47685958" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091523-044259</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 08:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Understanding Spatial Agglomeration: Increasing Returns, Land, and Transportation Costs (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-020723-041113">"Understanding Spatial Agglomeration: Increasing Returns, Land, and Transportation Costs"</a> (2024) by Hans R.A. Koster; Jacques-François Thisse (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Economic activities are concentrated on a small share of inhabitable land. In our view, this agglomeration is the outcome of a trade-off between increasing returns and transportation costs, which capitalizes into land rents. Our second baseline idea is that Tiebout-like sorting provides a general framework to handle a large array of problems in spatial economics. Cities have high housing prices because they are productive and offer high levels of amenities and public goods. Both production and amenity effects capitalize in the land rent at a particular location. Through the process of bidding for land, spatial sorting is the involuntary consequence of a myriad of individual decisions made by agents who pursue their own interests.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-020723-041113/Spatial_Economics_Agglomeration_Land_and_Sorting.mp3" length="20747333" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-020723-041113</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 05:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Experiments About Institutions (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091823-031317">"Experiments About Institutions"</a> (2024) by Michael Callen; Jonathan L. Weigel; Noam Yuchtman (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Institutions are a key determinant of economic growth, but the critical junctures in which institutions can change are not precisely defined. For example, such junctures are often identified ex post, raising several methodological problems: a selection on the outcome of institutional change; an inability to study beliefs, which are central to coordination and thus the process of institutional change; and an inability to conduct experiments to identify causal effects. We argue that critical junctures are identifiable in real time as moments of deep uncertainty about future institutions. Consistent with this conception, the papers reviewed (a) examine changes to institutions, i.e., the fundamental rules of the game; (b) are real-time studies of plausible critical junctures; and (c) use field experiments to achieve causal identification. We also advocate for more systematic measurement of beliefs about future institutions to identify critical junctures as they happen and provide an empirical proof of concept. Such work is urgent given contemporary critical junctures arising from democratic backsliding, state fragility, climate change, and conflicts over the rights of the marginalized.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091823-031317/Experiments_About_Institutions.mp3" length="14371764" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091823-031317</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 05:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Moral Boundaries (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091223-093730">"Moral Boundaries"</a> (2024) by Benjamin Enke (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article reviews the growing economics literature that studies the politico-economic impacts of heterogeneity in moral boundaries across individuals and cultures. The so-called universalism-versus-particularism cleavage has emerged as a main organizing principle behind various salient features of contemporary political competition, including individual-level and spatial variation in voting, the realignment of rich liberals and poor conservatives, the internal structure of ideology, and the moral content of political messaging. A recurring theme is that the explanatory power of universalism for left-wing policy views and voting is considerably larger than that of traditional economic variables. Looking at the origins of heterogeneity in universalism, an emerging consensus is that cross-group variation is partly economically functional and reflects that morality evolved to support cooperation in economic production. This insight organizes much work on how kinship systems, market exposure, political institutions, and ecology have shaped universalism through their impacts on the relative benefits of localized and impersonal interactions.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091223-093730/Moral_Boundaries_in_Political_Economy.mp3" length="27460285" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091223-093730</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 05:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Technology and the Global Economy (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-080218-025541">"Technology and the Global Economy"</a> (2024) by Jonathan Eaton; Samuel Kortum (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Interpreting individual heterogeneity in terms of probability theory has proved powerful in connecting behavior at the individual and aggregate levels. Returning to Ricardo's focus on comparative efficiency as a basis for international trade, much recent quantitative equilibrium modeling of the global economy builds on particular probabilistic assumptions about technology. We review these assumptions and discuss how they deliver a unified framework underlying a wide range of static and dynamic equilibrium models.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-080218-025541/Technology_and_the_Global_Economy.mp3" length="26720078" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-080218-025541</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 06:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>A Practical Guide to Weak Instruments (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-092123-111021">"A Practical Guide to Weak Instruments"</a> (2024) by Michael P. Keane; Timothy Neal (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We survey the weak instrumental variables (IV) literature with the aim of giving simple advice to applied researchers. This literature focuses heavily on the problem of size inflation in two-stage least squares (2SLS) two-tailed t-tests that arises if instruments are weak. A common standard for acceptable instrument strength is a first-stage F of 10, which renders this size inflation modest. However, 2SLS suffers from other important problems that exist at much higher levels of instrument strength. In particular, 2SLS standard errors tend to be artificially small in samples where the 2SLS estimate is close to ordinary least squares (OLS). This power asymmetry means the t-test has inflated power to detect false positive effects when the OLS bias is positive. The Anderson-Rubin (AR) test avoids this problem and should be used in lieu of the t-test even with strong instruments. We illustrate the practical importance of this issue in IV papers published in the American Economic Review from 2011 to 2023. Use of the AR test often reverses t-test results. In particular, IV estimates that are close to OLS and significant according to the t-test are often insignificant according to AR. We also show that for first-stage F in the 10–20 range there is a high probability that OLS estimates will be closer to the truth than 2SLS. Hence we advocate a higher standard of instrument strength in applied work.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-092123-111021/Better_Practices_for_Instrumental_Variables_Estimation.mp3" length="15010374" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-092123-111021</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Fertility in High-Income Countries: Trends, Patterns, Determinants, and Consequences (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-081523-013750">"Fertility in High-Income Countries: Trends, Patterns, Determinants, and Consequences"</a> (2024) by David E. Bloom; Michael Kuhn; Klaus Prettner (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  High-income countries have generally experienced falling fertility in recent decades. In most of these countries, the total fertility rate is now below the level that implies a stable population in the long run. This has led to concerns among economists, policymakers, and the wider public about the economic consequences of low fertility and population decline. In this contribution, we aim to (a) describe the main determinants of low fertility in high-income countries, (b) assess its potential economic consequences, (c) discuss adjustment mechanisms for individuals and economies, (d) propose a simple economic framework to analyze the long-run economic impacts of low fertility, and (e) draw lessons for economic policymakers to react appropriately. While the economic challenges of low fertility are substantial, a thoughtful and consistent policy response can mitigate most of the adverse consequences.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-081523-013750/Economics_of_Fertility_and_Population_Decline.mp3" length="17453747" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-081523-013750</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Modern Industrial Policy and the World Trade Organization (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-100223-041958">"Modern Industrial Policy and the World Trade Organization"</a> (2024) by Chad P. Bown (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article surveys the economics of industrial policy as it relates to the World Trade Organization (WTO). Motivated by concern that the modern use of industrial policy is emerging in ways that threaten cooperation in the international trading system, the article begins with the basic historical economic framework for tying industrial policy to underlying market failures. It then introduces the dominant economic understanding of the role played by the WTO, examining the WTO's rules on subsidies (and thus industrial policy), the unease with the evolution of the trading system's subsidy rules, gaps in knowledge, and important data and measurement shortcomings. The main part of the article examines four areas in which modern industrial policy operates differently and has become especially important for the trading system: China, supply chain resilience, supply chain responsiveness, and climate change. The article identifies the evidence to date, open questions, and potential paths forward for economic research to help inform policymakers’ efforts to restore international economic cooperation in trade and industrial policy.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-100223-041958/Industrial_Policy_Subsidies_and_the_WTO.mp3" length="20903191" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-100223-041958</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>The New Economics of Industrial Policy (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-081023-024638">"The New Economics of Industrial Policy"</a> (2024) by Réka Juhász; Nathan Lane; Dani Rodrik (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We discuss the considerable literature that has developed in recent years providing rigorous evidence on how industrial policies work. This literature is a significant improvement over the earlier generation of empirical work, which was largely correlational and marred by interpretational problems. On the whole, the recent crop of papers offers a more positive take on industrial policy. We review the standard rationales and critiques of industrial policy and provide a broad overview of new empirical approaches to measurement. We discuss how the recent literature, paying close attention to measurement, causal inference, and economic structure, is offering a nuanced and contextual understanding of the effects of industrial policy. We re-evaluate the East Asian experience with industrial policy in light of recent results. Finally, we conclude by reviewing how industrial policy is being reshaped by a new understanding of governance, a richer set of policy instruments beyond subsidies, and the reality of deindustrialization.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-081023-024638/The_New_Economics_of_Industrial_Policy.mp3" length="18116291" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-081023-024638</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Central Bank Independence: Views from History and Machine Learning (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-081623-032553">"Central Bank Independence: Views from History and Machine Learning"</a> (2024) by Nergiz Dincer; Barry Eichengreen; Joan J. Martinez (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We assemble an almost complete set of central bank statutes since 1800 to assess the legal independence of central banking institutions. We use these to extend existing indices of legal independence backward and forward in time. We document the trend toward increased independence post 1980 as well as an earlier, more limited movement in the direction of enhanced independence in the 1920s. We apply natural language processing to current statutes to corroborate our human-reader assessment. Using machine-learning methods, we quantify the extent to which topics in those statutes contribute to the independence measure based on our reading of the statutes. The topic with the largest positive contribution to explaining the cross-country variation in central bank independence encompasses disclosure, transparency, and reporting obligations. The topic with the largest negative contribution covers regulatory powers over inter alia securities markets that complicate the central bank's mandate, make accountability more complex, and render independence problematic.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-081623-032553/Central_Bank_Independence_Views_from_History_and_Machine_Learning.mp3" length="12526884" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-081623-032553</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 06:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>From Happiness Data to Economic Conclusions (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-081623-021136">"From Happiness Data to Economic Conclusions"</a> (2024) by Daniel J. Benjamin; Kristen Cooper; Ori Heffetz; Miles Kimball (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Happiness data—survey respondents’ self-reported well-being (SWB)—have become increasingly common in economics research, with recent calls to use them in policymaking. Researchers have used SWB data in novel ways—for example, to learn about welfare or preferences when choice data are unavailable or difficult to interpret. Focusing on leading examples of this pioneering research, the first part of this review uses a simple theoretical framework to reverse-engineer some of the crucial assumptions that underlie existing applications. The second part discusses evidence bearing on these assumptions and provides practical advice to the agencies and institutions that generate SWB data, the researchers who use them, and the policymakers who may use the resulting research. While we advocate creative uses of SWB data in economics, we caution that their use in policy will likely require both additional data collection and further research to better understand the data.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-081623-021136/Economics_of_Subjective_Well_Being_Surveys_and_Measurement.mp3" length="23457169" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-081623-021136</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 07:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Fiscal Federalism in the Twenty-First Century (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-081623-020713">"Fiscal Federalism in the Twenty-First Century"</a> (2024) by David R. Agrawal; Jan K. Brueckner; Marius Brülhart (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Fiscal federalism concerns the division of policy responsibilities among different levels of government. Many current economic and policy developments, such as globalization, environmental crises, and rising inequality, may not appear to be favorable to fiscal federalism, yet countries are further decentralizing their fiscal systems. We summarize the efficiency and equity aspects of fiscal decentralization, fiscal competition, fiscal externalities, and intergovernmental grants. The review introduces readers to theoretical reasons for/against a federalist structure. We discuss how federalism relates to classic problems in economics: externalities, inequality, spillovers, information, and aspects of political economy. Our review integrates both theory and empirics, while also focusing on the variety of federal systems in different countries, both developing and developed. We conclude by discussing how fiscal federalism is being shaped by economic, technological, and environmental changes, while discussing the effects of globalization, polarization, and global crises on the future of federal systems.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-081623-020713/Fiscal_Federalism_in_the_Twenty_First_Century.mp3" length="26053063" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-081623-020713</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 07:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Why Survey-Based Subjective Expectations Are Meaningful and Important (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091523-043659">"Why Survey-Based Subjective Expectations Are Meaningful and Important"</a> (2024) by Francesco D'Acunto; Michael Weber (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  For decades, households’ subjective expectations elicited via surveys have been considered meaningless because they often differ substantially from the forecasts of professionals and ex-post realizations. In sharp contrast, the literature we review shows that household characteristics and the ways in which households collect and process economic information help us understand previously considered puzzling facts about their subjective expectations. In turn, subjective expectations contribute to explain heterogeneous consumption, saving, investment, and debt choices as well as different reactions by similar households to the same monetary and fiscal policy measures. Matching microdata on households’ characteristics with the price signals the same households observe, their subjective expectations, and their real-world economic decisions is crucial to establishing these facts. Our growing understanding of households’ subjective expectations inspires several theoretical and empirical research directions and begets the design of innovative and more effective policy instruments.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091523-043659/Household_Subjective_Expectations_and_Economic_Choices.mp3" length="17085131" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091523-043659</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 07:29:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Negative Interest Rate Policies: A Survey (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-080323-042145">"Negative Interest Rate Policies: A Survey"</a> (2024) by Luis Brandão-Marques; Marco Casiraghi; Gaston Gelos; Güneş Kamber; Roland Meeks (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article surveys studies on the impact of central bank negative interest rate policies (NIRP). It reviews recent research on the effects of NIRP on financial markets, banks, households, firms, and the macroeconomy. Overall, policy rate cuts when interest rates are negative propagated along the yield curve, with the first policy cut below zero contributing significantly to the fall in longer-term yields. Lending and deposit rates also decreased following the adoption of NIRP. Based on the experience so far, bank lending volumes rose, and bank profits did not significantly deteriorate, although there was considerable heterogeneity in the effects. The impact of NIRP on inflation and output appears to have been comparable to that of conventional interest rate cuts.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-080323-042145/Review_of_Negative_Interest_Rate_Policies.mp3" length="14491085" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-080323-042145</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 07:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Climate Change Economics over Time and Space (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-072123-044449">"Climate Change Economics over Time and Space"</a> (2024) by Klaus Desmet; Esteban Rossi-Hansberg (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  With average temperature ranging from −20°C at the North Pole to 30°C at the Equator and with global warming expected to reach 1.4°C to 4.5°C by the year 2100, it is clear that climate change will have vastly different effects across the globe. Given the abundance of land in northern latitudes, if population and economic activity could freely move across space, the economic cost of global warming would be greatly reduced. However, spatial frictions are real: migrants face barriers, trade and transportation are costly, physical infrastructure is not footloose, and knowledge embedded in clusters of economic activity diffuses only imperfectly. Thus, the economic cost of climate change is intimately connected to these spatial frictions. Building on earlier integrated assessment models (IAMs) that largely ignored space, in the past decade there has been significant progress in developing dynamic spatial integrated assessment models (S-IAMs) aimed at providing a more realistic evaluation of the economic cost of climate change, both locally and globally. This review discusses this progress and provides a guide for future work in this area.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-072123-044449/Spatial_Economics_of_Climate_Change.mp3" length="17509264" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-072123-044449</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 07:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Alternatives to Bayesian Updating (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-100223-050352">"Alternatives to Bayesian Updating"</a> (2024) by Pietro Ortoleva (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We discuss models of updating that depart from Bayes’ rule even when it is well-defined. After reviewing Bayes’ rule and its foundations, we begin our analysis with models of non-Bayesian behavior arising from a bias, a pull toward suboptimal behavior due to a heuristic or a mistake. Next, we explore deviations caused by individuals questioning the prior probabilities they initially used. We then consider non-Bayesian behavior resulting from the optimal response to constraints on perception, cognition, or memory, as well as models based on motivated beliefs or distance minimization. Finally, we briefly discuss models of updating after zero probability events.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-100223-050352/Deviations_from_Bayesian_Updating.mp3" length="17843133" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-100223-050352</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 04:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Understanding Money Using Historical Evidence (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091923-040328">"Understanding Money Using Historical Evidence"</a> (2024) by Adam Brzezinski; Nuno Palma; François R. Velde (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Debates about the nature and economic role of money are mostly informed by evidence from the twentieth century, but money has existed for millennia. We argue that there are many lessons to be learned from monetary history that are relevant for current topics of policy relevance. The past is a source of evidence on how money works across different situations, helping to tease out features of money that do not depend on one time and place. A close reading of history also offers testing grounds for models of economic behavior and can thereby guide theories on how money is transmitted to the real economy.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091923-040328/Historical_Perspectives_on_Money_and_Monetary_Policy.mp3" length="22909766" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091923-040328</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 04:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Learning From Ricardo and Thompson: Machinery and Labor in the Early Industrial Revolution and in the Age of Artificial Intelligence (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091823-025129">"Learning From Ricardo and Thompson: Machinery and Labor in the Early Industrial Revolution and in the Age of Artificial Intelligence"</a> (2024) by Daron Acemoglu; Simon Johnson (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  David Ricardo initially believed machinery would help workers but revised his opinion, likely based on the impact of automation in the textile industry. Despite cotton textiles becoming one of the largest sectors in the British economy, real wages for cotton weavers did not rise for decades. As E.P. Thompson emphasized, automation forced workers into unhealthy factories with close surveillance and little autonomy. Automation can increase wages, but only when accompanied by new tasks that raise the marginal productivity of labor and/or when there is sufficient additional hiring in complementary sectors. Wages are unlikely to rise when workers cannot push for their share of productivity growth. Today, artificial intelligence may boost average productivity, but it also may replace many workers while degrading job quality for those who remain employed. As in Ricardo's time, the impact of automation on workers today is more complex than an automatic linkage from higher productivity to better wages.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091823-025129/Machinery_Labor_and_the_Age_of_AI.mp3" length="12538055" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091823-025129</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 04:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Monopsony Power in the Labor Market: From Theory to Policy (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-072823-030431">"Monopsony Power in the Labor Market: From Theory to Policy"</a> (2024) by José Azar; Ioana Marinescu (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Labor markets are not perfectly competitive: Monopsony power enables employers to pay workers less than the marginal revenue product of labor. We review three theoretical frameworks explaining monopsony power. Oligopsony models attribute it to strategic interactions among a limited number of firms. Job differentiation models cite imperfect job substitution and heterogeneous worker preferences. Search-and-matching models point to search frictions hindering instantaneous access to all available jobs. We then develop a theory-informed discussion of the empirical evidence on antitrust policies, policies that reduce barriers to job switching, and policies countering monopsony's effects on workers. Preventing mergers and regulating noncompetition agreements can increase wages by preserving competition among employers. Minimum wages can mitigate the effect of monopsony power by increasing wages without reducing employment. The insights garnered from both theoretical models and empirical evidence offer a road map for crafting policies that can enhance competition in the labor market.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-072823-030431/Monopsony_Theory_and_Labor_Policy.mp3" length="22413608" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-072823-030431</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 04:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Political Inequality (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-080223-040921">"Political Inequality"</a> (2024) by Julia Cagé (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Inequality in political participation and influence has strongly increased in recent decades, breeding economic inequality. In this review, we focus on three aspects of political inequality: the increasing concentration of both political and charitable donations, the growing gap in descriptive representation, and the persistent lack of substantive representation. Based on the existing literature as well as on novel evidence, we relate these aspects to the recent widening of turnout inequality. We then examine novel forms of participation—e.g., the rise of small donors in the United States—and the efficiency of policies aimed at improving representation. Finally, we discuss new avenues for research.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-080223-040921/Political_and_Economic_Inequality_in_Democracies.mp3" length="18609184" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-080223-040921</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Protests (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082423-032519">"Protests"</a> (2024) by Davide Cantoni; Andrew Kao; David Y. Yang; Noam Yuchtman (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Citizens have long taken to the streets to demand change, expressing political views that may otherwise be suppressed. Protests have produced change at local, national, and international scales, including spectacular moments of political and social transformation. We document five new empirical patterns describing 1.2 million protest events across 218 countries between 1980 and 2020. First, autocracies and weak democracies experienced a trend break in protests during the Arab Spring. Second, protest movements also rose in importance following the Arab Spring. Third, protest movements geographically diffuse over time, spiking to their peak before falling off. Fourth, a country's year-to-year economic performance is not strongly correlated with protests; individual values are predictive of protest participation. Fifth, the United States, China, and Russia are the most overrepresented countries in academic studies. We discuss each pattern's connections to the existing literature and anticipate paths for future work.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082423-032519/Understanding_Global_Protest_Patterns_and_Dynamics.mp3" length="20411341" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082423-032519</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Data and Markets (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082322-023244">"Data and Markets"</a> (2023) by Maryam Farboodi; Laura Veldkamp (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Big data is changing every corner of economics and finance. The largest firms in the US economy are valued chiefly for their data. Yet, these data are largely excluded from macroeconomic and finance research. We review work and relevant tools for measuring economic activity, market power, data markets, and the role of data in financial markets. We also highlight areas where future work is needed.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082322-023244/Data_and_Markets_An_Economic_Review.mp3" length="19968081" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082322-023244</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Advances in the Economic Theory of Cultural Transmission (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-090622-100258">"Advances in the Economic Theory of Cultural Transmission"</a> (2023) by Alberto Bisin; Thierry Verdier (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  In this article we survey recent advances in the economic theory of cultural transmission. We highlight three main themes on which the literature has made great progress in the last 10 years: the domain of traits subject to cultural transmission; the microfoundations for the technology of transmission; and feedback effects between culture, institutions, and various socioeconomic environments. We conclude by suggesting interesting areas for future research.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-090622-100258/Economic_Models_of_Cultural_Transmission.mp3" length="19245820" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-090622-100258</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>The Organization of Social Enterprises (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082222-075249">"The Organization of Social Enterprises"</a> (2023) by Robert H. Gertner (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Growing interest in the role of business entities in addressing social problems highlights the potential of social enterprises—organizations that cover all or most of their costs through revenue-generating business and have an objective to address a societal problem. A social enterprise can be an efficient and effective way to create social value by internalizing externalities, exploiting complementarities with commercial activities, providing better prices or quality to disadvantaged customers, and reducing the need for scarce philanthropic support. The challenges of managing an organization for financial success and social impact may limit their potential. Social enterprises can be for-profit or nonprofit organizations. The legal and institutional structure of for-profit and nonprofit governance and financing makes it challenging for a social entrepreneur to find a business model and organization structure to succeed.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082222-075249/Economics_of_Social_Enterprise_Organizations.mp3" length="21768368" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082222-075249</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Labor Market Insurance Policies in the Twenty-First Century (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082322-035621">"Labor Market Insurance Policies in the Twenty-First Century"</a> (2023) by Tito Boeri; Pierre Cahuc (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  The COVID-19 crisis was a stress test for unemployment insurance schemes as it involved a sudden and unexpected shutdown of a very large set of activities. This forced countries to introduce, often from scratch, income support schemes for workers under new forms of employment and for the self-employed. There was also a considerable expansion of short-time work schemes. As we move past this crisis, labor markets are likely to be characterized by substantial labor reallocation, and major innovations in labor market policy will be required to smooth consumption of workers involved in this reallocation. We survey the large body of research on schemes complementary to unemployment insurance to reduce the costs of reallocation. We focus on short-time work, partial unemployment insurance, and wage insurance and compare their properties to those of standard unemployment benefits. Next we present the main empirical results on the effects of wage insurance, partial unemployment insurance, and short-time work. In the final section we discuss directions for further research.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082322-035621/Flexible_Work_and_Unemployment_Insurance.mp3" length="19259109" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082322-035621</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Global Capital Allocation (2024) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-081623-020427">"Global Capital Allocation"</a> (2024) by Sergio Florez-Orrego; Matteo Maggiori; Jesse Schreger; Ziwen Sun; Serdil Tinda (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We survey the literature on global capital allocation. We begin by reviewing the rise of cross-border investment, the shift toward portfolio investment, and the literature focusing on aggregate patterns in multilateral and bilateral positions. We then turn to the recent literature that uses micro data to document patterns in global capital allocations. We focus on the importance of the currency of denomination of assets in international portfolios and the role that tax havens and offshore financial centers play in intermediating global capital. We conclude with directions for future research in this area.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-081623-020427/Reviewing_Global_Capital_Allocation.mp3" length="17939470" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-081623-020427</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Micro Propagation and Macro Aggregation (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082322-012833">"Micro Propagation and Macro Aggregation"</a> (2023) by David Baqaee; Elisa Rubbo (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article reviews a framework for studying the aggregation and propagation of microeconomic shocks in general equilibrium. We discuss the determinants of aggregate measures of real economic activity, like real GDP, real domestic absorption, and aggregate productivity in both efficient and inefficient environments. We also discuss how shocks from one set of producers are transmitted to other producers through prices and quantities. The framework we provide is amenable to generalization and can be used to study any collection of producers ranging from one isolated producer to an industry consisting of heterogeneous producers to an entire economy. We conclude with a brief survey of some of the applied questions that can be addressed using the analytical tools presented in this review and avenues for future work.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082322-012833/Aggregation_and_Propagation_in_Production_Networks.mp3" length="17085507" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082322-012833</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:22:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>How to Run Surveys: A Guide to Creating Your Own Identifying Variation and Revealing the Invisible (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091622-010157">"How to Run Surveys: A Guide to Creating Your Own Identifying Variation and Revealing the Invisible"</a> (2023) by Stefanie Stantcheva (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Surveys are an essential approach for eliciting otherwise invisible factors such as perceptions, knowledge and beliefs, attitudes, and reasoning. These factors are critical determinants of social, economic, and political outcomes. Surveys are not merely a research tool. They are also not only a way of collecting data. Instead, they involve creating the process that will generate the data. This allows the researcher to create their own identifying and controlled variation. Thanks to the rise of mobile technologies and platforms, surveys offer valuable opportunities either to study broadly representative samples or to focus on specific groups. This article offers guidance on the complete survey process, from the design of the questions and experiments to the recruitment of respondents and the collection of data to the analysis of survey responses. It covers issues related to the sampling process, selection and attrition, attention and carelessness, survey question design and measurement, response biases, and survey experiments.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091622-010157/Crafting_and_Conducting_Economic_Surveys_and_Experiments.mp3" length="21720095" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091622-010157</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Antitrust Reform: An Economic Perspective (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082222-070822">"Antitrust Reform: An Economic Perspective"</a> (2023) by Richard J. Gilbert (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  There is widespread dissatisfaction with existing antitrust enforcement. The European Union has enacted comprehensive legislation to address perceived antitrust limitations, and several proposals to amend US antitrust laws have followed its lead. Most of the actual and proposed laws target firms that dominate the digital economy, while others have measures to tighten antitrust enforcement more generally. Market power has increased in the United States and most advanced economies, but it has not been uniformly associated with higher prices or lower productivity. Nonetheless, antitrust reforms can benefit consumers and address concerns about the concentration and exercise of economic power. In the United States, legislation would be desirable to amend rulings that are excessively deferential to antitrust defendants. However, most enacted and proposed reforms include prohibitions or obligations that depart from traditional antitrust principles and create potential risks for consumer welfare.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082222-070822/Current_Trends_and_Challenges_in_Antitrust_Enforcement.mp3" length="33059304" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082222-070822</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Recent Developments in Partial Identification (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-051520-021124">"Recent Developments in Partial Identification"</a> (2023) by Brendan Kline; Elie Tamer (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  Identification strategies concern what can be learned about the value of a parameter based on the data and the model assumptions. The literature on partial identification is motivated by the fact that it is not possible to learn the exact value of the parameter for many empirically relevant cases. A typical result in the literature on partial identification is a statement about characterizing the identified set, which summarizes what can be learned about the parameter of interest given the data and model assumptions. For instance, this may mean that the value of the parameter can be learned to be necessarily within some set of values. First, the review surveys the general frameworks that have been developed for conducting a partial identification analysis. Second, the review surveys some of the more recent results on partial identification.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-051520-021124/Recent_Developments_in_Partial_Identification.mp3" length="5151791" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-051520-021124</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Regulating Collusion (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-051520-021936">"Regulating Collusion"</a> (2023) by Sylvain Chassang; Juan Ortner (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  We attempt to provide a systemic view of the process of regulating collusion, including detection and prosecution as well as bargaining between firms and regulators via consent orders, the production of evidence, and containment measures that may be taken if collusion cannot be addressed with more direct means. In addition, we try to do justice to the peculiarities of the legal system: Modeling the courts as they are, rather than as economists think they should be, is essential for economic analysis to improve the way collusion is regulated.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-051520-021936/Regulating_Collusion_Economic_Analysis_and_Legal_Perspectives.mp3" length="17069724" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-051520-021936</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 06:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Non-CES Aggregators: A Guided Tour (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082322-013910">"Non-CES Aggregators: A Guided Tour"</a> (2023) by Kiminori Matsuyama (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  The constant-elasticity-of-substitution (CES) aggregator and its demand system are ubiquitous in business cycles theory, macroeconomic growth and development, international trade and other general equilibrium fields; this is because the CES aggregator has many knife-edge properties that help to keep the analysis tractable in the presence of many goods and factors. However, this also makes it hard to tell which properties of CES are responsible for certain results. Furthermore, it is necessary to relax some of those properties for certain applications. In this article, I review several classes of non-CES aggregators, each of which removes some properties of CES and keeps the rest to introduce some flexibility while retaining the tractability of CES as much as possible. These classes are named after the properties of CES they keep. I explain how these classes are related to each other and discuss their relative strengths and weaknesses to indicate which classes are suited for which applications.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082322-013910/Beyond_CES_A_Tour_of_Non_CES_Aggregators.mp3" length="21015726" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082322-013910</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>New Thinking in Austrian Economics (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082322-021346">"New Thinking in Austrian Economics"</a> (2023) by Peter J. Boettke; Christopher J. Coyne (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This review discusses the unique features of Austrian economics and some of the recent contributions of this school of thought. We organize these contributions in different research “buckets” in the hope that this will be a useful guide to readers while demonstrating the ongoing relevance of the contemporary Austrian school of economics for advancing scientific discourse. The research buckets discussed include robust political economy, macroeconomics, monetary economics, entrepreneurship and the market process, development economics, behavioral economics, governance, social economy, collective action challenges related to natural disaster recovery and infectious disease, and war and defense.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082322-021346/Contemporary_Austrian_Economics_Applied.mp3" length="25585184" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082322-021346</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Cognitive Limitations: Failures of Contingent Thinking (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-091622-124733">"Cognitive Limitations: Failures of Contingent Thinking"</a> (2023) by Muriel Niederle; Emanuel Vespa (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  In recent years, experiments have documented a new mechanism that leads to failures of profit maximization: the failure of contingent thinking (FCT). This article summarizes key experimental findings, clarifies what constitutes an FCT, and outlines how FCTs can be tested in other environments. Subsequently, we relate FCTs to recent theoretical work on cognitive limitations in behavioral economics. Finally, we connect FCTs to suboptimal behavior documented in applied environments.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-091622-124733/Failures_of_Contingent_Thinking_in_Economics.mp3" length="16430487" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-091622-124733</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Parenting Promotes Social Mobility Within and Across Generations (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-021423-031905">"Parenting Promotes Social Mobility Within and Across Generations"</a> (2023) by Jorge Luis García; James J. Heckman (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article compares early childhood enrichment programs that promote social mobility for disadvantaged children within and across generations. Instead of conducting a standard meta-analysis, we present a harmonized primary data analysis of programs that shape current policy. Our analysis is a template for rigorous syntheses and comparisons across programs. We analyze new long-run life-cycle data collected for iconic programs when participants are middle-aged and their children are in their twenties. The iconic programs are omnibus in nature and offer many services to children and their parents. We compare them with relatively low-cost, more focused home-visiting programs. Participants in programs that enrich home environments grow up with better skills, jobs, earnings, marital stability, and health, as well as reduced participation in crime. The long-run monetized gains are substantially greater than the costs of the iconic programs. A study of focused home-visiting programs that target parents enables us to isolate a crucial component of successful programs: They activate and promote the parenting skills of child caregivers. The home-visiting programs we analyze produce outcomes comparable to those of the iconic omnibus programs. National implementation of the programs with long-run follow-up that we analyze would substantially shrink the overall Black-White earnings gap in the United States.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-021423-031905/Parenting_and_Social_Mobility.mp3" length="12245826" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-021423-031905</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 06:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>The Economics of Digital Privacy (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082322-014346">"The Economics of Digital Privacy"</a> (2023) by Avi Goldfarb; Verina F. Que (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  There has been increasing attention to privacy in the media and in regulatory discussions. This is a consequence of the increased usefulness of digital data. The literature has emphasized the benefits and costs of digital data flows to consumers and firms. The benefits arise in the form of data-driven innovation, higher-quality products and services that match consumer needs, and increased profits. The costs relate to the intrinsic and instrumental values of privacy. Under standard economic assumptions, this framing of a cost-benefit trade-off might suggest little role for regulation beyond ensuring consumers are appropriately informed in a robust competitive environment. The empirical literature thus far has focused on this direct cost-benefit assessment, examining how privacy regulations have affected various market outcomes. However, an increasing body of theory work emphasizes externalities related to data flows. These externalities, both positive and negative, suggest benefits to the targeted regulation of digital privacy.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082322-014346/The_Economics_of_Digital_Privacy.mp3" length="26003705" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082322-014346</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 06:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>The Economics of Border Carbon Adjustment: Rationale and Impacts of Compensating for Carbon at the Border (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-082322-034040">"The Economics of Border Carbon Adjustment: Rationale and Impacts of Compensating for Carbon at the Border"</a> (2023) by Lionel Fontagné; Katheline Schubert (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  International trade contributes directly to global greenhouse gas emissions, as the carbon content of high-emission products is priced differently in different countries. This phenomenon is termed carbon leakage. Thus, not putting a price on carbon is theoretically equivalent to an export subsidy, although that would be difficult to challenge in the context of multilateral trade law. Leakage can be alleviated by pricing the carbon embedded in imported products through a border carbon adjustment (BCA), be it a tax, a carbon tariff, or a regulation requiring the purchase of emissions allowances. The design of a BCA is a compromise between environmental effectiveness in preventing leakage, economic effectiveness in preserving competitiveness and ensuring acceptability, technical feasibility of the implementation, and World Trade Organization compatibility. An import-limited BCA is more effective than free emissions allowances in reducing leakage, but it does not preserve the export competitiveness of the country imposing it.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-082322-034040/Border_Carbon_Adjustments_Economic_Analysis.mp3" length="16763505" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-082322-034040</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 05:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Tertiarization Like China (2023) </title>
  <description><![CDATA[NotebookLM deep dive for
  <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-economics-071122-030026">"Tertiarization Like China"</a> (2023) by Xilu Chen; Guangyu Pei; Zheng Song; Fabrizio Zilibotti (Annual Review of Economics).

  The original article is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">CC BY 4.0</a>.

  Not checked for correctness. Not endorsed by the journal or the authors. AI makes mistakes.

  Abstract:
  This article documents a rapid shift toward services (tertiarization) of the Chinese economy since 2005, as evidenced by the significant increase in both employment and value-added shares of the service sector. Notably, our analysis reveals that a variety of measures of productivity growth have been greater in the service sector than in the manufacturing sector. Firm-level measures of dynamism corroborate this ongoing tertiarization trend, which is not limited to services used as inputs to industrial production but extends also to consumer services. These findings are robust across different growth accounting methodologies, including a recently proposed method by Fan et al. (2023) that addresses challenges associated with the measurement of quality improvements in service industries.
  ]]></description>
  <enclosure url="https://github.com/skranz/are_podcast/releases/download/annurev-economics-071122-030026/China_s_Rapid_Shift_to_Services_and_Productivity_Growth.mp3" length="13800461" type="audio/mpeg"/>
  <guid>annurev-economics-071122-030026</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 06:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>



</channel>
</rss>
